mattamyhomes.com 2018-08-27

# Mattamy Homes | Privacy Policy

This Privacy Policy has been prepared by Mattamy Homes (" **Mattamy** ", " **we** ", " **us** ", " **our** ") and sets out the manner in which Mattamy collects, uses, discloses and otherwise manages personal information.  The Privacy Policy also describes the privacy practices on the Mattamy website (the "Website") and through other interactions with consumers. 

## Collection and Use of Personal Information

**Guest Registry** : When you visit one of our sales centres and complete a Guest Registry form, we collect contact information such as your first and last name, mailing address, email address and mobile, work or home phone numbers. You may also choose to provide optional information such as your current housing situation, reason for moving, desired housing characteristics, family status, number of adults and children, age group and annual household income. We use the information provided on the Guest Registry form to better understand your needs, assist you in finding a suitable home and to send you tailored communications about Mattamy homes, products and services. We also use this information on an aggregate basis to better understand our customers and to improve our product and service offerings. 

**Buying a Home** :  When you complete an Agreement of Purchase and Sale for a residential property through Mattamy, we collect the information you provide on the Agreement including the first and last name and contact information (such as mailing address and telephone numbers) for each purchaser, real property description, and purchase amount.  We use this information for the purposes of facilitating the residential property transaction. We also collect information necessary to verify the identity of purchasers (such as a valid government-issued identification) as well as a personal cheque for deposit purposes.

**Requests for Mortgage Information** :  If you request information regarding the availability of home mortgage programs offered by Mattamy Home Funding in the United States, we collect your, and any co-borrower’s, personal information, including name, email address, employment and income, assets and liabilities, Social Security number and credit history.  Any information you provide in connection with your request for mortgage information will be forwarded directly to the appropriate Mattamy Home Funding affiliate, which will respond to your request or have a representative of Mattamy Home Funding contact you.  For additional information, please refer to the separate Privacy Policy for Mattamy Home Funding. 

**Warranty Registration and Requests** :  We collect certain personal information, including your name, email address, mailing address, telephone number and property closing date when you register for a new home warranty plan or when you make a warranty customer care request.  This information is used to complete the warranty registration and to fulfill your request for warranty-related services.  

**Website Registration** :  In order to access information, products, and services on a password-protected area of our Website, we may request certain personal information such as your name, mailing address, telephone number, email address and password that you select.  We use this registration information to provide and otherwise administer your online account or service you request. 

**Marketing Communications** :  When you complete a Guest Registry form or otherwise sign-up to receive information regarding Mattamy communities, homes, financial services and related products and services, we collect your contact information such as your name, mailing address, mobile, work or home telephone numbers and email address. We use the information you send you communications based on your interests by mail, email or telephone. You can opt-out of receiving future marketing and promotional communications at any time by clicking on the unsubscribe link included in our email communications or by contacting us as set out under “Contact Us” below.

**Referral Services/Tell-a-Friend** : If you choose to use one of our referral services to tell a friend about our Website or an employment opportunity, we will ask you for your friend’s name and email address.  We will send your friend a one-¬time email on your behalf inviting him or her to visit the site.  We store this information for the sole purposes of sending this one-time email and tracking the success of our referral program, and we do not use the names or email addresses submitted in these circumstances for any other purpose without consent to do so. You are responsible for ensuring that you only submit email addresses of individuals with whom you have a personal or family relationship and who would want to receive the message.

**Survey and Customer Research** :  From time to time, we may offer you the opportunity to participate in one of our surveys or other customer research. We may collect certain personal information such as your name and email address.  The information obtained through our surveys and customer research is used in an aggregated, non-personally identifiable form to help us understand our customers and to enhance our product and service offerings. 

**Customer Service** :  When you contact us with a comment, question or complaint, you may be asked for information that identifies you (such as your name, address and a telephone number) along with additional information we need to help us promptly answer your question or respond to your comment or complaint (for example, lot number, warranty enrollment number, etc.).  We may retain this information to assist you in the future and to improve our customer service and product and service offerings. We also use personal information to establish and manage our relationship with you and provide quality customer service. 

**Employment** :  In connection with a job application or related inquiry, you may provide us with certain personal information about yourself (such as that contained in a resume, cover letter, or similar employment-related materials).  This information will be used for the purpose of processing and responding to your application for current and future career opportunities.

##  Disclosure and Sharing of Personal Information

We will not disclose, trade, rent, sell or otherwise transfer your personal information, without your consent, except as otherwise set out herein. 

**Service Providers** :  Your personal information may be transferred (or otherwise made available) to our affiliates and other third parties who provide services on our behalf.  For example, we use service providers to provide services such as maintaining our Website, hosting our job application form, providing services related to our Website, sending electronic mail or other functions related to our business and services.  Our service providers are given the information they need to perform their designated functions, and are not authorized to use or disclose personal information for their own marketing or other purposes.

Your personal information may be maintained and processed by us, our affiliates and other third party service providers in Canada, the US or other jurisdictions.  In the event personal information is transferred to the US or other foreign jurisdiction, it will be subject to the laws of that jurisdiction and may be disclosed to or accessed by the courts (or related parties), law enforcement and governmental authorities in accordance with those laws. 

**Legal/Compliance** :  Mattamy, its affiliates and its Canadian, US and other foreign service providers may provide your personal information in response to a search warrant or other legally valid inquiry or order, or to another organization for the purposes of investigating a breach of an agreement or contravention of law or detecting, suppressing or preventing fraud, or as otherwise required or permitted by applicable Canadian, US or other law.  Your personal information may also be disclosed where necessary for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims and to investigate or prevent actual or suspect loss or harm to persons or property.

**Sale of Business** :  Personal information may be provided to third parties in connection with a prospective or completed business transaction, including a merger or sale (including transfers made as part of insolvency or bankruptcy proceedings) involving all or part of Mattamy or as part of a corporate reorganization or stock sale or other change in corporate control.

##  Cookies, Interest-Based Advertising, and Additional Information about our Website 

### **Visiting our Website**

We and/or our service providers collect IP (Internet protocol) addresses from all visitors to the Website and other related information such as page requests, browser type, operating system and average time spent on our Website.  This information is used to help us understand our Website activity, and to monitor and improve the Website. 

###  Cookies, Tracking Tags & Web Beacons

Our Website uses a technology called “cookies”.  A cookie is a tiny element of data that our Website can send to your browser, which may then be stored on your hard drive so we can recognize you when you return.  We use cookies on the pages on our Website where you are prompted to log in or that are customizable.  If you have registered with our Website, these cookies may let us know who you are and identify your browser as one that has visited the Website before, and may be necessary to access your account information (stored on our computers) in order to deliver products and personalized services. We also use cookies to provide us and our service providers with information about your use of the Website (such as web pages visited) that we will use to personalize our Website in accordance with your interests and assumed preferences. 

You may set your Web browser to notify you when you receive a cookie or to not accept certain cookies.  However, if you decide not to accept cookies from our Website, you may not be able to take advantage of all of the features of our Website. 

Our Website may also use a technology called “tracking tags” or “Web Beacons”.  This technology allows us to understand which pages you visit on our Website.  These tracer tags are used to help us optimize and tailor our Website for you and other future visitors to our Website.   
Our Website is not designed to respond to “do not track” signals received from browsers.

###  Analytics

We may use a third party such as Google Analytics to help us gather and analyze information about the areas that you visit on our Website. Such third parties may use technologies such as cookies, web server logs and web beacons. We use this information to evaluate and improve the customer experience and the convenience of our Website, and to help us evaluate some of the specific information related to your Website visits. For more information, see "[How Google uses data when you use our partners' sites or apps](http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners)".

###  Interest-Based Advertising

We may use third parties to serve our advertisements on other websites.  These companies may use cookies, tracer tags or web beacons to report certain information about your visits to our Website and other websites (such as web pages you visit and your response to ads) in order to measure the effectiveness of our marketing campaigns and to deliver ads that are more relevant to you, both on and off our Website. 

To find out more about the collection and use of information by third parties for behavioral advertising purposes, or if you would like to opt-out of certain third-party cookies and make selections about what online advertisement you choose to receive, you can visit the Digital Advertising Alliance website at <http://www.digitaladvertisingalliance.org/> or <http://www.aboutads.info/choices/> or the Digital Advertising Alliance of Canada website at [www.youradchoices.ca/choices](http://www.youradchoices.ca/choices). You can opt-out of interest-based ads from Google by visiting [adssettings.google.com](https://adssettings.google.com/authenticated).  

### Third Party Links

Our Website may contain links to other sites that we do not own or operate, including social media websites.  Also, links to our Website may be featured on third party websites on which we advertise.  Except as provided herein, we will not provide any of your personal information to these third parties without your consent.  We provide links to third party websites as a convenience to the user.  These links are not intended as an endorsement of or referral to the linked websites.  The linked websites have separate and independent privacy statements, notices and terms of use, which we recommend you read carefully.  We do not have any control over such websites, and therefore we have no responsibility or liability for the manner in which the organizations that operate such linked websites may collect, use or disclose, secure and otherwise treat your personal information. 

###  Social Media

We may offer you the opportunity to engage with our content on or through third-party social networking websites, plug-ins and applications. When you engage with our content on or through third-party social networking websites, plug-ins and applications, you may allow us to have access to certain information associated with your social media account (e.g., name, username, email address, profile picture, gender) to deliver the content or as part of the operation of the website, plug-in or application. When you provide information from your social media account, we may use this information to personalize your experience on the Website and on the third-party social networking websites, plug-ins and applications, and to provide you with other products or services you may request.

###  Safeguards and Retention 

We have implemented reasonable administrative, technical and physical measures in an effort to safeguard the personal information in our custody and control against theft, loss and unauthorized access, use, modification and disclosure.  We restrict access to your personal information on a need-to-know basis to employees and authorized service providers who require access to fulfil their job requirements. 

Your online access to certain of your personal information may be protected with a password you select. We strongly recommend that you do not disclose your password to anyone. We will never ask you for your password in any unsolicited communication (such as letters, phone calls or email messages).

We have personal information retention processes designed to retain personal information of our customers for no longer than necessary for the purposes stated above or to otherwise meet legal requirements.

###  Access to Your Personal Information

You have the right to access, update, and correct inaccuracies in your personal information in our custody and control, subject to certain exceptions prescribed by law. 

You may request access, updating and corrections of inaccuracies in personal information we have in our custody or control by emailing or writing to us at the contact information set out below.  We may request certain personal information for the purposes of verifying the identity of the individual seeking access to their personal information records.

###  Changes to the Privacy Policy

This Privacy Policy may be updated periodically to reflect changes to our personal information practices.  We will post the updated Privacy Policy on our Website.  Your personal information will be treated in accordance with the Privacy Policy in place at the time your personal information was collected, unless you otherwise consent. 

###  Contact Us

Please contact our Privacy Officer if:

  * you have any questions or comments about this Privacy Policy,

  * you wish to access, update, and/or correct inaccuracies in your personal information, or

  * you otherwise have a question or complaint about the manner in which we or our service providers treat your personal information.

You may contact our Chief Privacy Officer by email at steve.kahansky@mattamycorp.com or by mail at the following address:

Mattamy Homes  
66 Wellington Street W.  
Suite 5500  
Toronto, ON M5K 1G8

Attention:  Steve Kahansky
